Like you, dear fellow, I think that the French and German progressives have a great historical responsibility.
We are not merely confronting academic scenarios.
We are living a very dangerous moment.
And my presence here today by my Die Linke fellows' side aims at showing the danger we are facing.
The EU has entered a dislocation process,
and the worse aspects of this process are flowing out.
This is the situation we are facing now.
This is the situation we must confront.
We are deeply attached to the european ideal of peace and concord.
But this Europe has been methodically organized by the German right wing
as a machine that shocks the people of the EU with one another, compete with one another.
We must stop this crazy logic.
We have a responsibility, and you Germans as well.
Clearly, Mrs Merkel's government would like Europe to believe that you Germans are living heaven on earth.
In France, we are told that we should do the same as Germans.
Well, I'm ready to do this, but my german model is Oskar Lafontaine, not Mrs Merkel.
We do not want Mrs Merkel's model to become widespread to the rest of Europe.
Now, let me tell you what our objectives are.
We, the progressives, are ready to change Europe's organization deeply.
We reach out everyday to make this transformation possible.
However, if this transformation is not possible,
we will prefer the sovereignty of our people and the refusal of the destruction of our industry and of our homeland,
to this sort of nightmare that Mrs Merkel's Europe has become.
I want to make this clear for everyone.
Europe is a great idea, and it deserves better than becoming distorted as it is by Mrs Merkel and Mr Schäuble.
We refuse the brutality of the treatment of Ireland, Cyprus or Greece
I warn everyone that we will not let this happen.
This is why we are coming closer so vigorously to our fellows, with our progressive comrades, brothers and sisters.
We very well know that the responsibility lies with Mrs Merkel's government, not with the German people.
We know this. We have a lot of work to do, and that's what we came for today.